It is your duty to present your data in the most truthful way possible?
尽可能真实地展现你的数据 是你的责任
People can and do lie with their visualizations to deceive others.
人们能够而且真的会使用可视化来欺骗他人
One of the most common methods is in distorting the area of charts.
其中最常见的方法是歪曲图表的面积
Here's an example from Fox News that was created in 2012.
这个例子来自于 2012 年的福克斯新闻
The chart here is attempting to show you the change in tax rate.
这个图表试图向你展示税率的变化
It looks like a huge change.
这看起来变化很大
Something like five times increase.
好像增加了五倍
However, if you look at the actual numbers,
然而 如果你仔细观察实际的数字
it's only 35 percent to 39.6 percent.
税率仅仅是从 35% 增长到了 39.6%
A 13 percent increase or 4.6 percentage points.
增长率为 13% 或 4.6 个百分点
Humans tend to assume that the baseline of a bar chart is set to zero.
人们习惯于认为条形图的基线被设置为零
Here, the baseline was set to 34 percent,
但这里基线则被设定为 34%
which is out of line with our assumptions.
跟我们的假设完全不同
The creator of this graphic,
这张图的创建人
likely meant to deceive viewers into believing
可能有意想欺骗读者 让他们相信
the tax rate change was much larger than it actually was.
税率的变化远比实际变化大得多
This brings us to the lie factor,
这为我们引出了失真系数
a concept introduced by Edward Tufte in Visual Display.
这是 Edward Tufte 在《Visual Display》一书中提出的概念
Yup, him again.
是的 又是他
You really should find this book if you haven't yet.
强烈建议你读这本书
The lie factor compares the size of the effect in
失真系数把数据图表的效应值
a graphic to the size of the effect in the data.
与数据本身的效应值进行比较
By effect, I mean the difference you're comparing.
这里的效应 指的是你正在比较的差异
For example, you're comparing the heights of the bars in the tax rate chart.
例如 你在比较税率图中条形的高度
So the effect would be how much taller the right bar is than the left bar.
效应就是右边的条形比左边的条形高出多少
To calculate the lie factor,
要计算失真系数
you divide the effect size by the graphic with the effect size by the data.
你需要用图形的效应值去除数据本身的效应值
As an example of this,
作为例子
I'll use this figure,
我将使用这张图
which is also a great example of chart junk.
它也是一个图表垃圾的好例子
It's actually ambiguous which aspect of the doctor images is encoded in the data.
数据到底对医生图片的哪个方面进行了编码？
The height, the area,
是高度？是面积？
it turns out the height of the doctors is proportional to the percentages.
事实证明 医生的高度是与百分比大小成比例的
But we actually perceive the visual area as the encoding for the data.
但是 我们事实上很容易会把图片的面积理解成了数据的编码
Since we're comparing the area of the doctors,
因为我们在比较医生图片的面积大小
I'll use that to calculate the graphical effect.
我将使用面积来计算图形的效应值
Making a rectangle around this largest doctor,
在这个最大的医生周围画一个矩形
it's 437 pixels tall and 181 pixels wide.
高为 437 像素 宽为 181 像素
So it has an area of around 79,000 square pixels.
因此 它的面积为大约 79,000 平方像素
The middle doctor has an area around 30,500 square
中间的医生面积为大约 30,500 平方像素
pixels and the smallest doctor is 16,500 square pixels.
最小的医生面积为 16,500 平方像素
Let's work out the lie factor for the comparison between 1964 and 1990.
我们现在来计算失真系数 用来比较 1964 年和 1990 年
The visual effect is how much larger the doctor is in 1964.
视觉效应为 1964 年时医生的面积
That is 79,000 minus 16,500 divided by 16,500 or 3.79.
79,000 减去 16,500 再除以 16,500 结果为 3.79
So the difference between the size of the doctors is
因此 医生图片面积之间的差为
379 percent the size of the smaller doctor.
较小医生面积的 379%
The effect size and the actual data is 27 minus 12 divided by 12, or 1.25.
而实际数据的效应值为 27 减去 12 再除以 12 结果为 1.25
So the difference in the data is 125 percent larger than the 1990 data point.
因此 数据的差是 1990 年数据的 125%
Dividing these, the lie factor is 3.0 or 3.
将这两个值相除 失真系数就可以被计算出来 为 3.03
Any lie factor greater than 1 suggests that your visual is misleading.
大于 1 的失真系数表明你的可视化具有误导性
The larger the factor,
该系数越大
the more misleading the visual.
可视化就越具有误导性